<dashboard>
    <label>KV Store Tools</label>
    <row>
        <panel>
            <html>
				<h3><a id="Utilities_for_the_Splunk_App_KeyValue_Store_4"></a>Utilities for the Splunk App Key-Value Store</h3>
				<p>The KV Store Tools app is a fork of the "Gemini KV Store Tools" app for Splunk, and includes the following features:</p>
				<ul>
				<li>KV Store backup: Backup KV Store collections.</li>
				<li>KV Store restore: Restore KV Store collections from backup jobs. Deletes the existing collections before restoring (unless otherwise specified).</li>
				<li>KV Store migrate: Copy KV Store collections from one Splunk search head to another. Deletes the existing collections before restoring (unless otherwise specified).</li>
				<li>Delete Keys: Delete KV Store records from a collection based on _key values in search results.</li>
				<li>Delete Key: Delete KV Store records from a collection based on user input.</li>
				<li>KV Store alert action: Similar to outputlookup, but can be toggled on/off by users that have permissions to edit search jobs without modifying the search.</li>
				</ul>
				<hr/>
				<h3><a id="KV_Store_Backup_16"></a>KV Store Backup</h3>
				<p>This functionality is implemented through a generating search command.  Simply run or schedule a search like the following:<br/>
				<code>| kvstorebackup app=&quot;app_name&quot; collection=&quot;collection_name&quot; path=&quot;/data/backup/kvstore&quot; global_scope=&quot;false&quot;</code></p>
				<p>The backup process will write one or more .json or .json.gz files (one for each collection).</p>
				<p><strong>Arguments</strong>:</p>
				<ul>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> app: &lt;string&gt; - Set the app in which to look for the collection(s).  (Default: All)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> path: &lt;string&gt; - Set the directory path for the output files. (Default: the the setting in the app Setup page)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> global_scope: [true|false] - Specify the whether or not to include all globally available collections. (Default: false)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> collection: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the collection to backup. (Default: All)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> compression: [true|false] - Specify whether or not to compress the backups. (Default: false)</p>
				</li>
				</ul>
				<p><strong>Best Practice</strong>: In a Search Head Cluster (SHC) environment, map a shared network drive to all members so that the backed-up collections are available to all of them.</p>
				<hr/>
				<h3><a id="KV_Store_Restore_37"></a>KV Store Restore</h3>
				<p>This functionality is implemented through a generating search command.  Run a search such as:<br/>
				<code>| kvstorerestore filename=&quot;/backup/kvstore/app_name#collection_name#20170130*&quot;</code></p>
				<p>The restore process will delete the KV Store collection and overwrite it with the contents of the backup.</p>
				<p>Arguments:</p>
				<ul>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> filename: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the file to restore the data from.</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> append: [true|false] - Specify whether or not to append records to the target KV Store collections. (Default: false - deletes the collection prior to restoring)</p>
				</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Running the search command with no arguments will list existing backups in the default path.</p>
				<hr/>
				<h3><a id="KV_Store_Migrate_52"></a>KV Store Migrate</h3>
				<p>This functionality is implemented through a generating search command.  Configure your remote Splunk credentials in the Setup page, then run a search such as:<br/>
				<code>| kvstoremigrate app=&quot;app_name&quot; collection=&quot;collection_name&quot; global_scope=&quot;false&quot; append=&quot;true&quot; target=&quot;remotehost&quot;</code></p>
				<p>The migration process will delete the remote KV Store collection and overwrite it with the contents of the backup, unless append=true is set.</p>
				<p>Arguments:</p>
				<ul>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Required)</em> target: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the hostname to migrate collections to.</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> port: &lt;integer&gt; - Specify the target splunkd port on the remote host. (Default: 8089)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> app: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the app to find the collection(s) within. (Default: All)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> global_scope: [true|false] - Specify the whether or not to include all globally available collections. (Default: false)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> collection: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the collection to migrate. (Default: All)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> append: [true|false] - Specify whether or not to append records to the target KV Store collections. (Default: false - deletes the collection prior to migrating)</p>
				</li>
				</ul>
				<hr/>
				<h3><a id="KV_Store_Delete_Keys_73"></a>KV Store Delete Keys</h3>
				<p>This functionality is implemented through a streaming search command.  Run a search such as:<br/>
				<code>| inputlookup lookup_name where domain=&quot;*splunk.com&quot; | deletekeys collection=&quot;collection_name&quot;</code></p>
				<p>Deletes records from a KV Store collection based on _key value in search results</p>
				<p>Arguments:</p>
				<ul>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> app: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the app to find the collection within. (Default: All)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Required)</em> collection: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the collection to delete the data from.</p>
				</li>
				</ul>
				<hr/>
				<h3><a id="KV_Store_Delete_Key_86"></a>KV Store Delete Key</h3>
				<p>This functionality is implemented through a generating search command.  Run a search such as:<br/>
				<code>| deletekey collection=&quot;collection_name&quot; key=&quot;key_value&quot;</code></p>
				<p>Deletes a specific record from a KV Store collection based on _key value</p>
				<p>Arguments:</p>
				<ul>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Optional)</em> app: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the app to find the collection within. (Default: All)</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Required)</em> collection: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the collection to delete the data from.</p>
				</li>
				<li>
				<p><em>(Required)</em> key: &lt;string&gt; - Specify the value for the _key field in the collection record.</p>
				</li>
				</ul>
</html>
        </panel>
    </row>
</dashboard>